hi I'm evolutionary biologist brett
weinstein my hope in this first video is
to give you a sense of my intent for
this channel so that you'll know what to
expect
I've seen some speculation online about
whether or not the purpose of the
channel is to talk about politics or
biology and I should take this
opportunity to clear that up I'm
interested in what we call politics but
my belief is that it is also an
evolutionary dynamic and so while I will
not avoid the topic entirely I can say
that when we talk politics I will come
at it from a biological perspective I've
also been asked who this channel is for
so let me tell you a few things about
that when I was in school I was not a
very good student and for the last 15
years I've been teaching in a way that I
think would have worked for me if I had
encountered it that said I've also had
many students who were successful in a
classic school context and they also did
well with my teaching style my favorite
students are often the ones who come
through the door though thinking that
they are not scientifically minded my
belief is that all people are born with
minds that natively do science and that
modern schooling drives out that impulse
by penalizing the asking of certain
kinds of questions I love questions and
the more difficult the better so if you
also like questions welcome what kinds
of topics will we address well we're
going to spend some time on basic
evolutionary framework that is to say
the lens is to look through and the
tools with which to build up a
scientific understanding we will spend
some time on fun questions why do males
have nipples why are we take a look
those sorts of things there will be
important questions are human beings
evolutionarily monogamous or not there
will be difficult questions what is war
what is genocide what is oppression
where do they come from and
evolutionarily speaking is there
anything that we can do about them and
there will be speculative questions does
humanity have a future and if so what
might it look like there are also
challenges for this channel my favorite
thing about teaching has been close
interaction with students both in the
classroom and in the field that allows
for an informal mode of interaction
that's going to be very difficult to
accomplish over the Internet
that said I'm sure we can figure out how
to do it and I'm glad you're here